Unknown: I hit... Is it not recording?
DM: It's not recording.
Unknown: No.
DM: No.
Unknown: What the hell? It said recording when I clicked it.
DM: None of, none of this has been recording.
Unknown: No.
DM: That's too bad.
Kenzo: No. We have nothing to feed the AI about what happened.
DM: I'll, I'll have to write notes.
Unknown: We have to recap right now.
Unknown: Um, quick recap.
Kenzo: What, there's, there's dude with no face and a garden and we all had seeds.
Unknown: We all...
Unknown: That was cool.
Wellby: It turned out to be a nice dude after all.
Unknown: What's that?
Wellby: It turned out to be a nice guy after all.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: He was great. He's gonna be, uh, Kenzo's future teacher.
Unknown: We teleported with great success.
Unknown: We did. We absolutely...
Delwath: Just for the record, the teleport was 100% successful.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: If you hear any rumors that it was a failure, those are just rumors.
Unknown: Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm.
Unknown: Totally. Trying to smear, trying to smear Seeker's reputation.
Unknown: Smear campaign against Seeker. [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: Um, wait. So we started out in the deadly marshmallow ice swamp.
Unknown: We started out in the deadly marshmallow ice swamp.
Seeker: And made a soft and fuzzy-
Unknown: A mist
Unknown: ... mist.
Unknown: Mist.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: That was great.
Seeker: And then we steered that, and then-
Unknown: Uh, we shot the bow.
Unknown: Wellby shot the arrow of seeking.
Unknown: Shot the arrow.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Unknown: We followed it.
Delwath: And then, and then we got to the blue scary blue lights that we just-
Unknown: Oh, yeah
Unknown: ... um-
Seeker: Well, no, no, I was trying to go from the beginning 'cause we...
Delwath: That was after the, right after the bow was the blue lights.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah. The blue lights. Yeah.
Unknown: Oh, you're right. The blue lights.
Delwath: Not the, not the teleport, the other blue lights that we're trying to turn-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah. The blue lights
Delwath: ... that we're trying to turn the air to, to s-
Unknown: Yeah
Unknown: ... to burn a stone.
DM: Well, Wellby noticed the air was about to-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... shift and-
Delwath: And you turned into... You turned our ship into a crude, a crude boat sailing on the open sea with the sky above.
Unknown: And then we sailed through stone for a while.
Unknown: Sailed through stone, yeah.
Delwath: And then the arcane eye random directions found-
Kenzo: 'Cause there were three arcane eyes, and the third one...
Unknown: First two were of stone, and the third one found the-
Unknown: Found the garden
Unknown: ... the garden.
Unknown: The orchard.
Delwath: The orchard. And then we went to the no face orchard.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: And, um-
Unknown: Oh, wait. We didn't have faces
Unknown: ... we didn't have faces. Yeah.
Unknown: [coughs]
Unknown: We had a silver face.
Unknown: We got our faces back, right?
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Unknown: Eventually, I think.
Unknown: Eventually.
Unknown: Wait, wait. Does Kenzo still not have a face?
Unknown: No, he... I mean-
Unknown: I could, I could not have a face
DM: ... as long as you don't...
DM: It's up to Kenzo.
Kenzo: But I can, I can void... I can now do that.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Cool.
Delwath: Um, Kenzo just made his face disappear by being, like, one with the void.
Delwath: And Delwath turned his face silver with the silver mask.
Delwath: Ken- uh, uh, Wellby-
Unknown: Wellby wore a hat
Unknown: ... Wellby wore a hat that turned into his skin.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Right.
Seeker: Seeker, I tried to do it to myself.
DM: Seeker attempted to void mine like Kenzo-
Unknown: Oh, right
DM: ... but it failed.
Unknown: Because his mind is too distractible.
DM: And the, the silent orchard keeper-
Unknown: Just made your face go around
DM: ... and then we-
Unknown: Restored his beauty
Delwath: ... had a bunch of fruit.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Including one where we saw Frankar talking to an efreeti.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Kenzo: And there was a pomegranate fruit with the jade eye.
Unknown: Pomegranate fruit with the jade eye in front of it.
Unknown: And then the honeydew with the,
Unknown: with the chap-
Unknown: With the monastery
Unknown: ... with the monastery.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: And then we successfully teleported, uh-
Unknown: Wait, wait. And then we all got, we all...
Unknown: And then-
Unknown: Oh, and I got the glass dirt.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Also.
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: Seeker got glass dirt.
Kenzo: Uh, Kenzo communed with the tree and then got a chaos ki.
Unknown: Oh, right. Got a chaos ki.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Unknown: And then-
Delwath: Delwath took a fruit, uh, an elven sisila fruit.
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: And Wellby-
Unknown: Wellby took the emergency exit fruit
Kenzo: ... well, what's your, what's your fruit gonna do?
Unknown: It's-
Unknown: Delwath
Delwath: ... um, it's gonna tell Delwath...
Delwath: Uh, Delwath is, like, very pri- He's, like, a little embarrassed to explain what his fruit is.
Delwath: It's about finding, like, home.
Unknown: And it was-
Unknown: That's not embarrassing. That's very cute.
Unknown: It's, you know, it's a little bit-
Unknown: Right. It's personal
Unknown: ... it's like... And then-
Unknown: Very personal
Unknown: ... uh, elves have trouble with vulnerability.
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: Yeah. [laughs]
Unknown: And then you attempted to teleport-
Unknown: Actually, Delwath is happy to tell you about it
Unknown: ... and Seeker did amazing.
Unknown: Delwath's come a long way.
DM: Yeah. You attempted to teleport, and Seeker did amazing.
Seeker: Yeah. Where the goal was to find something similar to the monastery.
Unknown: And we found...
Unknown: Right.
Delwath: We... No, no. The goal was to teleport somewhere where we could find a more sturdy ship.
Unknown: Because-
Wellby: The goal was to go to the damn monastery [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Do not listen to Wellby.
DM: Wellby's bow got a little skeptical of everybody but Wellby.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
DM: You teleported to a conduit that, when you appeared, had a image of the
DM: monastery, but then it vanished before you got pulled into it.
DM: You got pulled into the conduit, and Seeker tried to make Vindristjarna-
Unknown: Vindristjarna. [laughs]
DM: ... and failed 'cause it was too complicated.
Unknown: Right.
DM: And instead made a big flat stone that you got teleported to.
Unknown: Right. And then we were traveling on that for a while.
Kenzo: Then there were a bunch of stone boars.
Unknown: Oh, right. In the pool of nothingness.
Unknown: But then we made a wake that had nothingness.
Unknown: Seeker made a wake of nothingness.
Unknown: Made a wake of nothingness, and then it got-
Delwath: And the world rotated on the right axis.
Unknown: Yeah. It went pari- perpendicular, and the boars went another way, and then we went the other way.
Unknown: That was so cool.
Kenzo: And then I, I definitely stayed awake after that.
Unknown: And then-
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs] So I'm gonna let somebody else narrate it, but I was totally awake.
Delwath: Then, then, then we got to the monastery, and we-
Unknown: Right
Unknown: ... and we, um-
Unknown: There were monks
Unknown: ... encountered the, um-
DM: The least human of the monks were just hands that-
Unknown: Right
Unknown: ... that wanted some thresholds
Unknown: ... the hands who wanted... Right.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: And we told them the story about the Garamjala Desert, a story about the door, uh, that-
Unknown: In the Eudomes' tower
Unknown: ... it, and a story about the Rainbow Bridge.
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: Mm.
Delwath: And then we met the emotion monks.
Delwath: And the emotion monks, we, uh...
Delwath: K- Delwath calmed one with suggestion to get it to
Unknown: speak out its grief.
Unknown: Tim's like, "It's not recording again."
Unknown: Is it recording?
DM: Yeah. It's, it's recording, but I can't...
Unknown: You can't what?
DM: I can't tell if it, like, paused partway through.
Unknown: What? What's going on with this phone?
DM: I don't know. Maybe we need somebody else's phone.
Unknown: It's still recording right now, right?
DM: It's recording right now. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Unknown: Very good.
Delwath: And then Delwath did a grief monk with suggestion.
Delwath: Kenzo, uh, did a-
DM: Kenzo meditated
Delwath: ... meditated with a monk.
Unknown: Wellby, uh-
Unknown: Wellby abused his rogue abilities
DM: ... abused. Seeker abused his bard abilities.
DM: Right.
Unknown: His ar- arcana.
Unknown: And now we're...
Delwath: Now we're, now we're engaged with-
DM: Now you're dealing with the-
Delwath: ... most human-like monks who are acting out their various things.
Delwath: And, and Delwath, um-
Delwath: Uh, pretended to be a student even though he knows everything, and-
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Damn.
DM: And left is a-
Delwath: Although Delwath actually knows the least of anybody in the party-
DM: Right
Unknown: ... by a significant margin.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Left is a monk that is, um...
Unknown: Yeah, so there's a sparring monk, a-
DM: A sparring monk, a praying monk, and a,
DM: and a student monk.
Unknown: So Kenzo goes to the praying monk and sits down and prays with him.
DM: Okay.
DM: Uh,
DM: what's, what's your...
DM: You're, you're just praying? Are you like...
DM: What ability are you using or what skill?
Unknown: Uh, insight.
DM: Insight? Okay.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Go ahead.
DM: So you're trying to just kind of get into the scene with this monk-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... just understand-
Unknown: Well, what's the, what's, what's the monk praying about?
DM: Well, you can't tell. It's, it's like not...
DM: These are incomplete-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, but like-
DM: ... and you need to complete the story
Kenzo: ... the extent that I can understand, can I get a-
Unknown: Isn't it a monk of Bhishma?
DM: They're monks of Bhishma, so it's-
Unknown: Bhishma.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Are you an initiate of Bhishma?
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Then, then is it a young monk?
DM: No, these are... Every single one of these were the...
Unknown: Yeah. Got it. Got it. Got it. Got it
DM: ... remember, they were all the masters.
Unknown: Oh, cool, okay.
DM: But you're like a master at this point.
Unknown: Yeah, exactly. Yeah, so, so, so Kenzo will do some advanced, uh, you know, some advanced Bhishma praying.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: He'll sit and, uh, he'll, he'll, he'll do the, the, you know...
DM: I, I... Yeah, okay, so insight is good for this.
DM: Roll insight.
Unknown: 15.
Unknown: Uh-oh.
DM: Um-
Unknown: Broke inspiration.
Delwath: Should, shouldn't Kenzo get advantage because he's a monk of Bhishma, I mean Bhishma?
DM: Yeah. Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah. That makes sense.
DM: [laughs] Okay.
Unknown: I don't think, I don't think Kenzo should fail.
DM: Fine, fine, fine. Yes, you get advantage.
Unknown: 17.
DM: Eh, damn it.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: What skill, what skill are you using?
Unknown: Insight.
Kenzo: My insight's only... How do you guys have like plus 17 and shit?
Unknown: My insight's-
Unknown: It's very ch- I only...
Unknown: My max is plus 11.
Kenzo: Mine's plus 10. I guess my stealth is plus 11.
DM: No, your insight's pretty good.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: It's just, it's just, um, all of these crazy people who have plus 17s because-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... they have expertise in things.
Unknown: Yeah,
Unknown: yeah.
DM: Um,
DM: 17 is like so close.
Unknown: Mm.
Unknown: I think it should just work 'cause it doesn't seem right that Kenzo would fail.
DM: What about w- uh, m- uh, inspiration? Just grab a bardic.
DM: Yeah. You'll definitely succeed with a bardic.
DM: Bardic inspiration, yeah.
Unknown: The two D12s, pick higher?
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: All right, nine.
Unknown: So, uh-
DM: Okay. Yeah, yeah.
Unknown: 26.
DM: Yeah. No, I mean,
DM: my predetermined minimum DC was 18, so.
Unknown: Okay. That's good.
DM: Um-
Unknown: It's good as a warrior
DM: ... it ranges from 18 to 25-
Unknown: Yeah, as a warrior
DM: ... depending on...
DM: Um,
DM: so,
DM: um,
DM: you sit down and you begin to pray, and you're, you're sort of, um,
DM: you know, going through some of the forms like, like when you commune with nature and stuff.
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
DM: Like the sort of, um, you know, opening your mind.
Unknown: Mm.
DM: And the first thing you notice is you begin to feel the sort of thoughts and the mind of this monk next to you.
DM: Um, and it begins to solidify and sort of drift towards you.
Unknown: Mm.
DM: And you sense it also kind of doing the same thing, and your communes with nature is like locked together.
Unknown: Yeah. What I do is like, as I...
Kenzo: 'Cause you know, there's, there's probably some like, you know, chant or something-
DM: Right
Kenzo: ... you know. And then like if I s- if I sort of s- I, I try to lock him into my, uh...
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: So the monk then climbs out and,
DM: um, sits next to you cross-legged in prayer.
Delwath: Uh, are all the monks from the previous ones?
Unknown: Do we have like a ghostly shift?
DM: Yeah, yeah.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: They're all following you.
Unknown: Cool.
DM: The last one is sparring.
DM: Oh, and teacher.
Unknown: Teacher.
DM: Sorry, student.
Unknown: Student, yes.
Unknown: Um-
DM: Yeah, that's, that's I kind of...
DM: Seeker has to kind of auto succeed on.
Unknown: Seeker, um-
DM: [laughs]
Delwath: I think everybody should have auto succeeded except me.
DM: Right. [laughs]
Seeker: Ra- Raise it, Seeker raises a piece of illusory chalk and turns to a, a vast chalkboard behind him and, uh-
Unknown: And erases it
Seeker: ... erases it with his sleeve a little bit and says, "Welcome," type, uh, writes-
DM: [laughs]
Seeker: ... "Welcome to the introductory," and then he lets go of the chalk and turns.
Unknown: It keeps writing behind him.
DM: [laughs]
Seeker: "Introductory session of our special topics seminar."
Unknown: How to survive in Limbo.
Unknown: What's that?
Seeker: No, no, it's actually just says, "Special topic seminar."
Seeker: Uh, and begins to ask the student questions about their personal interests and life journey to, in order to begin to assess, uh, where to begin the lesson.
Unknown: Yeah, that's good.
DM: [laughs]
Seeker: Learning about who they are and what they're interested in learning about.
DM: Um,
DM: so the, the student is not quite, um...
DM: They're still insubstantial, but each time, each time they reappear, um, you can see like sort of on the scroll where they're sort of taking notes, um, different
DM: sort of, uh, sketches of
DM: historical Dunmari buildings like the, um,
DM: like the, um, palace in Tokra that was like clearly an interest in sort of Dunmari history.
Unknown: Mm.
Seeker: And, uh, so I try to sort of dig deeper and figure out which, you know, geographic region of Dunmar and
Unknown: period of history they're interested in.
DM: They're not substantial enough to communicate that yet.
Seeker: Oh, okay. Well, I try to look at their drawings and, and-
DM: You recognize them. They're...
DM: It's mostly T- it's all pla- it's all buildings you've seen in Tokra.
Unknown: Mm.
DM: It's like Tokra history.
Seeker: Mm. And so I begin to lecture on
Unknown: my knowledge of Tokra. [laughs]
Delwath: But we actually researched a fair bit about the history of Tokra when we were going after the werewolves.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Delwath: There was a bunch of notes that Seeker would've known about like-
DM: Right.
Seeker: And then I, I make an interesting digression about my own experiences.
Seeker: Didn't we, did we dig or use a tunnel on Tokra?
Unknown: Yes.
DM: Yes, you did.
Unknown: Does the monk start like yawning and like
DM: No.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Make a, make a...
DM: The monk is interested. Seeker's a pretty good teacher.
DM: Make a history check
Unknown: That's another 12
DM: Plus 17.
DM: [dice clattering]
Unknown: That's 24.
Delwath: So wait, the minimum DC is 18.
Unknown: Why are you making them take, make checks?
DM: Oh, that's true.
Unknown: Plus 17.
DM: Right. You automatically succeed.
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: It's 24, yeah.
DM: Um,
DM: yes, I hadn't done the math.
DM: Uh,
Unknown: the, the student is actually very interested
DM: as you begin to talk about your, like...
DM: You know, you get distracted talking about architecture, and there's a di- digression into the history of various kinds of architecture, and dwarven architecture versus
DM: human architecture, and the student becomes more and more solid as you digress further and further from the topic.
DM: Um-
Seeker: Into the underground tunnels and the battle with the werewolves.
DM: Right. And then finally, you're just talking about the battle with the werewolves, and it's not history at all, but they're very interested.
Seeker: Well, it was a crucial sort of turning point historically, maybe in the history of the entire world, which is the, the rise-
DM: Oh, that's true
Unknown: ... of the-
Unknown: The rise of the what?
DM: That was the first time-
Unknown: The ladder
DM: ... the ladder came into play.
Unknown: Oh my God.
Unknown: Oh.
DM: Was the werewolves.
Delwath: It turns out it's a special seminar on the history of ladders.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: No, of the ladder.
Unknown: The ladder.
DM: Right.
Unknown: Of course.
DM: And the, the monk solidifies next to Spea- Seeker, leaving only the sparring.
Kenzo: [laughs] Was it, "He, he, he who climbs so that you may rise?"
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: That's the AI generated epithet about the ladder, which was nonsensical.
Unknown: No, it wasn't. It was so good.
Unknown: It was, uh...
Unknown: It was like the, the-
Unknown: "He has climbed so you may rise," or-
Unknown: Yeah, "He has climbed so you may rise."
Unknown: "He has climbed so you, you, you may rise."
Unknown: Something to the effect of that.
DM: No, but that's the exact opposite of it.
DM: The ladder sees the world.
Unknown: Correct.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: You have climbed so I may rise.
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: So Wellby will go over to the person sparring and, um, start to match what they're doing, like he'll watch for a few beats, and then, like, take the, like mirroring the
Wellby: motions that they're making. So like as they're blocking, he'll kick up to attack, uh, and so on, and just almost like dancing with them over
Unknown: and over and over again.
DM: Yeah. Make a, make an attack roll.
Unknown: 27.
DM: Okay, so you're-
Unknown: Wait, wait a minute.
Unknown: Where did that number come from?
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Wait, did,
DM: did you... [laughs] Did you just make up a number?
Seeker: Well, he, he said it quickly. You didn't notice?
DM: No, I didn't notice.
DM: [dice clattering]
Delwath: [laughs] Here, I rolled for you. 47, uh, wait, zero plus.
Unknown: 17, I think.
Unknown: 37.
DM: No, it's not...
DM: For an attack roll, it's only plus 11 or something.
Delwath: Well, I rolled a 20. You gotta add 31.
Unknown: Just making these rolls up as I go.
Unknown: [laughs] And no one's even gonna say anything about it.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Wow.
Unknown: You can keep it. You chose well.
DM: [coughs]
DM: I thought you had rolled before you went to sit down on the couch or something.
Unknown: That's true.
Unknown: I rolled, yeah. [laughs]
DM: Um,
DM: in any case-
Unknown: I thought that for a second. I was like, "No." [laughs]
Unknown: No you didn't.
DM: [laughs] You match the monk and begin sparring with it.
DM: And with the,
DM: all of the monks here that are,
DM: uh, pantomiming, you crash through the last barrier
DM: with a retinue of monks who solidify into people as you cross into an open monastery,
DM: uh, with a,
DM: uh...
DM: So it's like the cl- it's like the, a cloister, so there's, there's a,
DM: an open courtyard, pretty big, a couple hundred feet across, with this building in the center of it, a small domed building in the center of it.
DM: The, and then the, the cloisters have sort of a, a shaded extent that comes over, and you can see that there's monks.
DM: It's sandy in the middle, um, but there's monks that are sweeping, there's monks that are sort of doing walking circle meditations.
DM: Everything that you see is, like, very repetitive and, um, sort of strictly choreographed.
DM: Uh, the n- the monks that, um, that are following you sort of stumble out, um, and, and look around, like, briefly awed, and then
DM: sort of quickly begin resuming tasks.
DM: And as they, as they carry out these tasks, sweeping, praying, a couple of them are sparring.
DM: Um, there's, there's some that look like they're m- they're making scrolls or writing something on paper.
DM: Um, there's some that are, uh,
DM: you know, what looks like meal prep or something like that.
DM: And as these, these monks that you rescued continue these activities, they start, they become more solid over time as they repeat these choreographed
DM: behaviors. Like when they f- when you first pull them through,
DM: they're thin, they're sort of,
DM: uh, desaturated and almost translucent, still sort of misty.
Unknown: Is somebody making hot water?
Unknown: Yes.
DM: And as they begin to repeat these motions over and over, they begin to, like the flesh begins to solidify on them.
Kenzo: It's like Back to the Future in the...
DM: Mm-hmm.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: None of the monks seem to look like they're particularly interacting with you.
DM: [laughs]
Kenzo: Are there, are the, the ones that are, like, coming back, are they kind of conscious?
Kenzo: Are they, like, more, are their souls and consciousnesses, like, more normal?
Kenzo: Or are they just, like, automatons?
DM: No, no, no. They're, um,
DM: uh...
DM: What it feels like in soul sight is, is sort of like there's fuzz that's slowly melting away and revealing.
Unknown: Hmm.
Delwath: I wonder if they're the ones who, like, have faded, have, like, failed at being-
Delwath: The ones who are outside are the ones who, like, didn't
Delwath: s- who, like, Limbo started to take, right?
Unknown: Oh, yeah. That was the whole implication.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: The ones that we first interacted with-
Unknown: Yeah
Unknown: ... were the most fucked up and destroyed.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: And the closer we are to the monastery-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah
Unknown: ... the more ordered they are.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: It's, I mean, it, you, you c- this is the...
DM: I mean, the idea is that the more they, like, as they continue these kind of-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... very structured behaviors-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah
DM: ... the kind of Limbo fuzz begins to-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... melt away.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: It, it would take some time for them, like-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... you still sense they're s- they're still kind of fuzzy, right?
DM: But they're getting less fuzzy
DM: as they-
Unknown: Cool
DM: ... carry out these activities.
Unknown: Excellent.
Delwath: Um, do we see a jade statue?
DM: Well, the jade statue's in the building in the middle.
Unknown: Ah, right. So let's-
Unknown: Yeah, let's go to the-
Unknown: Yeah. Here we go
Unknown: ... let's go.
Unknown: Carefully avoiding the-
Unknown: I mean, we'll, like-
Unknown: ... geometries of the sweeping monks
Delwath: ... st- let the pattern, like be very careful not to disturb the-
DM: Right, not to disturb the pattern.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: We all walk synchronized, in lockstep.
DM: Right.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Actually, we should. Yeah.
Unknown: We should.
Unknown: Right. Yup.
DM: Um-
Unknown: Like we've never practiced marching before.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: So as you approach this central building, the door swings open
DM: by itself, and you can see inside, the interior is a nearly perfect copy of, although in smaller scale, of the Temple of the Eight Divines in Drankor.
Unknown: Whoa.
Unknown: Oh.
DM: Except
DM: that the art has shifted, and it's now stories that, Kenzo, you recognize from...
DM: And actually,
DM: Seeker did, like, most of the Bhishma initiation, too.
DM: It's, like, the stories from the-
Unknown: Oh, yeah
DM: ... Bhishma Temple that are now-
Unknown: Oh, you forgot that we-
Unknown: Oh, you're also... Yeah, that's right
DM: ... but Seeker didn't, like, accept the, you know, will you die and be resurrected thing.
Unknown: Yeah, you did most of the... I forgot.
DM: Um-
Unknown: Right
DM: ... so it's like that, except the stories have been replaced by those stories, by the...
DM: So there's, like, illuminated illustrations on the ceiling of, you know, Bhishma leading the, um, the Dunmari, of, like, Bhishma, um, pray, like, leading everybody
DM: in prayer, Jeevali being resurrected.
DM: Kind of the story of the, you know, the death and rebirth that was the Festival of Rebirth at the very beginning of the campaign.
Kenzo: Wait, and, uh, in Drankor, this temple was the one sanctuary place that we kept going back to, right?
DM: Yeah, this was where R- Rai had been for-
Unknown: Yes
DM: ... many years in Drankor.
Unknown: Yes, yes, yes.
DM: Yes. And in the middle of the
DM: building is a statue of jade, missing a hand.
Unknown: Do you think it's Rai?
DM: The-
Unknown: Nah, probably not
DM: ... the, the features look worn, almost eroded.
DM: Like, you can't make out, um,
DM: out details and, but you hear immediately a v- a voice in, in your head.
DM: Um,
DM: "Did Dimataur find you?
DM: Or did he send you?
DM: What brings you here?"
Unknown: No way.
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: Wow.
Unknown: Cool.
Unknown: Yes.
Unknown: Uh.
Seeker: Yes, we have met Dimataur.
Unknown: Apollyon's dead.
Kenzo: Uh, Kenzo, uh, takes, takes the, the staff with, uh, Rai's hand on it and, uh, says, uh, "Uh, um, I think this is yours."
Unknown: And he,
Kenzo: uh, brings the, the hand over.
DM: "I think it makes little difference to me now."
Unknown: Damn it. [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs] He came all this way.
Unknown: He came all this way to give you a hand.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: And you don't even want it?
Unknown: You just-
DM: We'll just go. We'll just go.
Unknown: Fine.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: We struggled for [laughs] so, so long.
DM: [laughs]
Wellby: No, no. Why, why little difference?
DM: Y-
DM: you did not...
DM: He seems confused for a moment.
DM: "Dimataur did not bring m- my message?"
Unknown: What was the message?
Unknown: Wait, are we forgetting a message?
DM: No. [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Dimataur might have forgotten a message.
Unknown: Damn it, Dimataur.
Wellby: Rai, have you met Dimataur?
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: [laughs] Di- um, Dimataur's, uh,
Unknown: he's had some adventures.
Wellby: He got old. It's been 30 years.
Unknown: He, um...
Unknown: He's doing well now.
Delwath: He is doing well. Uh, we left him in
Unknown: charge?
Seeker: In charge of the circular island.
DM: [laughs] Uh,
DM: n- n- no, too much to discuss.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: What was the message
Wellby: that he was to have delivered?
DM: There is...
DM: [sighs]
DM: When we tried
DM: some years ago,
DM: a few years only I think, although time passes strangely here-
Unknown: Right
DM: ... to
DM: close the portal to Limbo,
DM: I brought a bunch of Dunmari monks into
DM: this place, and I have
DM: done the best I could to
DM: keep them from fading, although...
DM: He stops for a minute.
DM: I see you have so- brought some back from the edge.
DM: I, I thank you for that.
DM: But
DM: only a fraction of my effort
DM: goes there, because
DM: nearby- Nearby as far as
DM: distances in this place are concerned, which has little actual meaning.
DM: There is a
DM: focus of stability,
DM: a
DM: seed of the material plane or something that has precipitated a, a, an island of order of a kind in this place.
DM: And the entity that is
DM: controlling
DM: that seed has been
DM: seeking to drag
DM: Limbo and the material plane closer and closer together,
DM: perhaps intermeshing them entirely.
DM: And I have been trying to stop that, but we are balanced on a knife edge.
Unknown: Mm.
DM: And I cannot leave here or the monks will die, and I cannot take them
DM: from this place or...
DM: Well, I've
DM: have no idea what might happen should this
DM: entity succeed in their goal, but
DM: certainly it would not be good for the material plane.
Delwath: Does the entity have the flavor of Cha'mutte?
DM: No.
Unknown: What are the odds?
DM: This thing is far, far older than Cha'mutte.
Unknown: Oh, boy. Okay.
Delwath: I mean, I thought Cha'mutte predated time.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Oh, boy.
Unknown: Oh.
Unknown: There is a wound
Unknown: at Isingue.
DM: Yes, I know. That is what I went to close.
DM: I realize now it was not a portal, it was something more complicated.
Unknown: We've come to believe it's a vortex.
DM: Ah.
DM: It makes sense.
DM: Is that why you're here?
Unknown: Indeed.
Seeker: We've read that the way to heal it is from this side, not the other.
Seeker: That we'll have to draw the Limbo activity away from
Unknown: With a piece of order.
DM: Well, yes, of course.
DM: That is,
DM: that is what I told Dimataur.
DM: Some powerful Dunmari sorcerer if he could find one.
DM: Although only one of you looks Dunmari.
DM: And he looks at you, and you do not appear to be a sorcerer.
Unknown: I'm not, yeah.
DM: But
Unknown: He's kind of
DM: Should not matter so much as long as one of you is...
DM: Well,
DM: it may be a challenge, actually.
DM: I believe that this
DM: fragment of stability is some kind of
DM: hyper dense
DM: series of runes that must be read in precisely the right order, and unfortunately, my eyes no longer work.
Unknown: Hmm.
Unknown: Well-
Unknown: I love the runes
Unknown: ... that's good news. Yeah, he's good with the runes.
Kenzo: Uh, what do you know of this entity?
Unknown: Or what can you tell us?
DM: I believe they are
DM: born of this plane,
DM: perhaps one of the original inhabitants of this plane,
DM: somehow
DM: captured and
DM: grown strong by the
DM: influence of this
DM: fragment of the material plane that has seeded a
DM: vector of stability.
Unknown: Wait, is it the Orchard Keeper?
DM: No.
DM: No. [laughs] The Orchard Keeper is something different.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Delwath: The, the Orchard Keeper also was...
Delwath: We could have taken the Orchard Keeper. I mean, the Orchard Keeper we knew could, right?
Unknown: Oh, right.
DM: Plus, the Orchard Keeper was not...
DM: Your inference is that the Orchard Keeper was from
DM: somewhere totally alien-
Unknown: Oh, right
DM: ... not from Limbo.
Unknown: Not from Limbo.
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: Hmm.
Unknown: Um,
Delwath: right. So we need to go to this place, take this piece of order, bring it to the rift, use it to-
Unknown: Pull it back
Unknown: ... pull it back.
Unknown: Easy enough, it sounds.
Delwath: Yeah, like what, what could go wrong?
Unknown: It's only the, you know,
Unknown: original-
Unknown: Inhabitant
Unknown: ... inhabitant of Limbo.
Unknown: Limbo.
Unknown: Like, you know.
Kenzo: How do we find this, uh, this piece of stability and order?
DM: That is not hard. I can guide you easily enough.
Unknown: And once we're there?
DM: Well, then you'll be on your own.
DM: This is why I told Dimataur I needed help.
DM: One alone can do little when I have two impossible tasks to achieve.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: What, what are the two tasks?
Unknown: Keeping the monks alive.
DM: Keeping the monks alive and-
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: Closing the rift
DM: ... closing the rift. Both require my full attention
Unknown: Once we-
Unknown: Wait. Sorry, go ahead
Kenzo: ... once we, uh, engage with the entity, do you have any
Kenzo: guidance or, or advice?
DM: All I can tell you is this:
DM: There are...
DM: I have observed the
DM: nature of life here, such as it is,
DM: and I believe that
DM: this...
DM: Well,
DM: there are things that live in Limbo,
DM: but they are
DM: so unstable and changeable that even as they grow larger and larger and more powerful, they turn
DM: into nothing so much as great weather fronts that travel across the land but have no will or purpose behind them.
DM: Or rather, it is better said, their will and purpose changes from moment to moment such that they can never accomplish anything.
DM: And eventually they grow so big that they fragment into tiny
DM: motes of possibility
DM: that grow.
DM: Sometimes you will see what look like beasts moving through the landscape
DM: that are
DM: several of these filaments grown together, and they will eventually merge and grow into bigger and bigger
DM: locuses of c- chaos.
DM: My belief is that this creature
DM: is what happens when one of these great
DM: chaos storms
DM: passes over a locus of stability
DM: and gains a fixed purpose and ability to control its form.
Delwath: So hold on. Did, do we need...
Delwath: The locus of stability itself is what we need, right?
DM: Yes.
Unknown: And that's what the runes are written on, you think?
Delwath: Okay. So we don't actually have to kill the creature.
DM: No.
Unknown: Uh,
Unknown: okay. [laughs] I mean, we might end up having to kill the creature.
Unknown: But in theory...
DM: Hmm.
DM: Okay.
Kenzo: Kenzo, uh, so th- the, the statue's speaking in our mind, right?
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: So it hasn't moved at all even.
DM: Has not moved at all.
Seeker: It is solid jade.
Kenzo: Kenzo will, uh, approach the statue and says, um,
Unknown: "Uh,
Kenzo: Rai, I know you don't know me, but, uh, I've carried a piece of your hand with me since I was
Kenzo: a small child. My parents found a piece of you in the deserts,
Kenzo: and we have, over these past many years-"
DM: I have seen you in dreams, yes.
Unknown: Oh, you have?
Unknown: That's good to know.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Some of my dreams, I believe.
Unknown: What's that?
Unknown: I've seen...
Unknown: You've seen me in your dreams?
Unknown: 'Cause I've seen a lot of your dreams.
DM: I've seen you in those dreams, yes.
Kenzo: Wow. Didn't know that worked that way.
Unknown: Hmm.
Unknown: Well, in any case,
Unknown: it has been
Kenzo: quite a lot of effort as we have, uh,
Kenzo: collected these fragments, and they have been
Kenzo: a big part of how we've been able to get here.
Kenzo: As you can imagine, it's not been, uh, straightforward to find you here in Limbo.
Kenzo: So even if it may not be, uh, as useful as you'd like now, it feels right to give this back to you.
DM: I,
DM: I appreciate that.
Kenzo: And, uh, Kenzo, like, kinda, "Ergy, ergy, ergy," like, unscrews the-
DM: [laughs]
Kenzo: [laughs] The, the, the jade hand from, uh, the top of his, uh, staff, and then, you know, goes over and, and, uh, you know, respectfully, uh, and humbly
Unknown: puts
Kenzo: the, puts the hand back onto, uh, Rai's stump.
DM: Sort of fuses there.
DM: There's a sort of,
DM: um, brief sort of moment of,
DM: you know,
DM: kind of a relaxed sigh in your mind.
DM: You notice that when you put the hand on that, like, most of the rest of the statue is actually quite worn.
DM: Like, it's, you know, it's like a sort of ancient statue that's, like, been eroded in places, and it's, like, all the, all the bits other than the hand
DM: is somewhat eroded and, and weathered.
DM: And it's not that noticeable, but in contrast to the, like, new hand, it's very clear.
DM: And you do get a sense, like a, a sense through your mind like,
DM: you know, this is a nice, this is nice.
DM: Like, it's,
DM: you know, the effort of sustaining this for
DM: 30 years, even if it hasn't been 30 years here, is non-trivial.
DM: And so
DM: there is a, like a,
DM: you know, some relief as you attach the hand, like this helps.
Delwath: What preparations can we make to go to this place?
DM: It is...
DM: I mean, it is not far. I have
DM: relied on the relic of stability myself to keep this place.
Unknown: What, um,
Delwath: is it fixed in form or are we likely to encounter
Delwath: changes like in the rest of Limbo?
DM: Well, it is
DM: within the domain of
DM: the,
DM: of the order of this
DM: relic.
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: But does the...
Unknown: Sorry, what I'm trying to get at-
DM: Does not mean that it is not, uh, possible for the entity that rules there to change things at whim.
Delwath: That's what I was trying to get at. Should we anticipate dangers from the entity shifting the ground underneath us?
DM: I would expect great danger, yes, as I am sure they do not wish to
DM: sacrifice this relic,
DM: and especially seem interested in
DM: bringing Limbo and the material plane closer.
DM: There have been
DM: moments when things have shifted and I've had to
DM: push back,
DM: and
DM: some of my charges have been lost over time in those moments when my concentration has
DM: foundered slightly.
DM: This is why I,
DM: when I could, asked
DM: for help, for I don't know how much longer I can
DM: sustain this.
Unknown: So should we take a little, a little break?
DM: Yeah. This is, I mean, this is a great time if,
DM: you know-
Kenzo: Feel like we got a little discussion going on here and, uh-
DM: Yeah, yeah.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: That was a great-
DM: I was gonna say, yeah
Seeker: ... session though because one of the...
Unknown: I just think it was nice to do the recaps. It's like,
Unknown: it felt like a long session because a lot of things happened.
Unknown: Yeah. Which is, there was a great pacing to it because we were trying to save as we went.
Unknown: Yeah, that was awesome.
Seeker: Uh, the Limbo mechanic is really good.
Unknown: See, Limbo's the best, man.
DM: Yeah. Should let, let them win.
DM: Let Limbo leak into the material plane and just, you know, turn everything into-